UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
That was close.
그것은 가까웠다.
I know, right?
나도 알아, 그렇지?
What happened here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Who's in there?
거기 누구야?
Mommy.
엄마.
-What? -"Mommy"?
-무엇? -"엄마"?
What…
뭐…
Mom.
엄마.
Daughter.
딸.
She's your daughter?
그 사람이 당신 딸이에요?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
The truth is…
진실은…
My name is Kim Bom, and I'm Kim Mi-sook's daughter.
내 이름은 김봄이에요. 저는 김미숙 딸이에요.
Did you sneak her in when you moved in here?
그녀를 몰래 들여보냈나요? 언제 여기로 이사왔어?
No, she was at a children's home back then.
아니요, 그 사람은 어린이집에 있었어요 그때.
I only saw her on the weekends,
주말에만 봤는데,
but she became curious about where I lived.
하지만 그녀는 궁금해졌다 내가 살았던 곳에 대해.
I was planning on keeping her for just one more night.
난 그녀를 지킬 생각이었어 딱 하룻밤만 더.
I told you my chocolate kept disappearing.
내 초콜릿이 계속 사라진다고 했잖아.
Yehppee!
응피!
KIM BOM, KIM MI-SOOK'S DAUGHTER 5TH ROOMMATE OF ROOM 301
김봄, 김미숙 딸 301호실의 5번째 룸메이트
Only I sensed her.
나만 그녀를 느꼈어요.
I'm quite sensitive and perceptive, you see.
제가 꽤 예민한 편이에요 그리고 통찰력이 있습니다.
Where did you sleep this past week?
지난 주에 어디서 잠을 잤나요?
I sleep together with Mommy in her bed.
나는 엄마 침대에서 함께 잔다.
Wait.
기다리다.
In our room?
우리 방에?
You didn't know?
몰랐어요?
So much for being perceptive.
지각력이 너무 많습니다.
Hold on.
기다리다.
You all remember the orientation from move-in day, right?
오리엔테이션은 다들 기억하시죠? 입주일부터죠?
The RA made it clear then
그때 RA가 분명히 해줬어요
that no visitors are allowed under any circumstances.
방문객이 허용되지 않는다는 것 어떤 상황에서도.
That kid cannot live here.
그 아이는 여기서 살 수 없어요.
Mi-sook, this could get you evicted.
미숙아, 이러면 너 쫓겨날 수도 있어.
Hey, kid.
안녕, 꼬마야.
What's with the glaring?
눈부신 게 뭐죠?
Glaring at me won't change a thing!
나를 노려봐도 아무것도 바뀌지 않아!
ROOM 301 ONCE AGAIN!
301호실을 다시 한 번!
My mommy has no reason to move out of the dorms.
엄마는 이유가 없어 기숙사에서 나가려고.
Of course, she does.
물론 그렇습니다.
Look, kiddo.
봐, 꼬마야.
This is the Seoul City Dormitory for Single Female Workers.
서울시립기숙사 입니다 미혼 여성 근로자를 위한.
My mommy isn't married.
우리 엄마는 결혼하지 않았어요.
My mommy is a single mom, and she's a single female worker.
우리 엄마는 싱글맘이고, 그리고 그녀는 미혼 여성 노동자입니다.
Single mom?
미혼모?
What about her father?
그녀의 아버지는 어떻습니까?
He's been unreachable since I told him about the pregnancy.
그 사람은 연락이 닿지 않았어 내가 그에게 임신 사실을 말한 이후로.
How terrible.
정말 끔찍해요.
I don't have anyone to look after her while I work,
난 아무도 없어 내가 일하는 동안 그녀를 돌보기 위해
so I was planning to have her stay at a children's home
그래서 나는 그녀를 머물게 하려고 계획 중이었어 어린이집에서
just until she starts school.
그녀가 학교에 들어갈 때까지만요.
I moved in here so I could save as much as possible until then.
절약하려고 여기로 이사왔어 그때까지 최대한.
I'm sorry for startling you all.
모두 놀라게 해서 미안해요.
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
No need to apologize.
사과할 필요는 없습니다.
You're still too young yourself.
당신은 아직 너무 어리거든요.
But still,
하지만 여전히,
child-rearing challenges and dorm rule violations
육아 문제 그리고 기숙사 규칙 위반
are two separate issues.
두 가지 별개의 문제입니다.
Have you no compassion?
동정심이 없나요?
I can't believe kids nowadays.
요즘 애들은 못 믿겠어요.
We could all end up in trouble if we're caught and grilled.
우리 모두가 곤경에 처할 수도 있어요 우리가 잡혀서 구워지면.
What trouble?
무슨 문제요?
Are you hiding something?
뭔가 숨기고 있나요?
No.
아니요.
It's your RA.
당신의 RA입니다.
Room 301, open this door immediately.
301호, 당장 이 문을 열어주세요.
I told you!
내가 말했잖아!
Hide her.
그녀를 숨기세요.
Hide inside.
안에 숨어.
Go. Hurry.
가다. 서두르다.
I heard some shouting earlier.
아까 어떤 사람이 소리치는 걸 들었습니다.
"Hey! Glaring at me won't change a thing!"
"야! 나를 노려봐도 아무 것도 바뀌지 않아!"
Gosh.
이런.
Hong Jang-mi
홍장미
started a fight with her
그녀와 싸움을 시작했다
after gobbling up all her pricy chocolates in the fridge!
꿀꺽 삼킨 후에 그녀의 값비싼 초콜릿은 모두 냉장고에 있어요!
They're really expensive.
정말 비싸요.
I was saving them to savor each bite.
한입 한입 맛보려고 아껴두었어요.
No, I can explain.
아니요, 설명할 수 있습니다.
She's got sticky fingers.
그녀는 끈적끈적한 손가락을 가지고 있어요.
Well, not terribly sticky.
뭐, 별로 끈적이진 않네요.
Just a bit.
조금만.
Ms. Hong Jang-mi.
홍장미씨.
That's two demerit points for you.
그것은 당신에게 두 가지 벌점입니다.
What?
무엇?
Wait, five gets you evicted.
잠깐만요, 5명이면 당신은 쫓겨날 거예요.
And I get two, just like that?
그리고 나는 두 개를 얻습니다. 그렇게요?
STATEMENT OF REMOR…
유감 성명…
Ms. Hong Jang-mi.
홍장미씨.
You can erase one demerit point by writing a ten-page statement of remorse.
써서 벌점 1점 지울 수 있어요 10페이지 분량의 반성문.
How could I have remorse when I did nothing wrong?
내가 어떻게 후회할 수 있겠는가? 내가 아무 잘못도 안 했을 때?
I'm really sorry, Jang-mi.
정말 미안해 장미야.
I know this may sound shameless,
뻔뻔하게 들릴 수도 있다는 걸 알아요.
but could you just let it slide until the end of the year?
하지만 그냥 미끄러지도록 놔두실 수 있나요? 연말까지?
That's when the exam for full-time employment is scheduled.
그땐 시험이잖아 정규직 채용이 예정되어 있습니다.
If I pass, I'll be eligible for an internal company loan,
합격하면 합격할 수 있겠네요 내부 회사 대출의 경우
and Bom and I could find our own place.
그리고 봄과 나는 우리만의 자리를 찾을 수 있었다.
I'll write that remorse statement.
그 반성문을 쓰겠습니다.
I'll also make sure to teach Bom to stay out of the way--
봄님도 꼭 가르쳐드릴게요 방해가 되지 않도록--
No.
아니요.
That would be breaking the rules.
그것은 규칙을 어기는 것입니다.
Besides, what would you teach her?
게다가 그녀에게 무엇을 가르칠 건가요?
To be wary of others and hide?
남을 경계하고 숨으려고?
To be invisible?
눈에 띄지 않으려면?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
Hong Jang-mi, could your words cut any deeper?
홍장미, 당신의 말이 좀 더 깊어질 수 있나요?
Even the King of the Underworld would show more mercy than you.
지하세계의 왕이라도 당신보다 더 많은 자비를 베푸실 것입니다.
Hey, add your two cents too.
이봐요, 당신도 2센트를 추가하세요.
Perhaps we could strive for a warmer sense of communal living--
어쩌면 우리는 노력할 수도 있을 것 같아요 좀 더 따뜻한 공동체 생활을 위해
You all helped me keep my job, and I'm thankful for that.
여러분 모두 제가 직업을 유지하는 데 도움을 주셨고, 그리고 나는 그것에 대해 감사합니다.
That's why I'm letting it slide today.
그래서 오늘은 이만 미루겠습니다.
But by tomorrow…
하지만 내일까지는…
I'd like the kid gone.
그 아이가 없어졌으면 좋겠어요.
Room 301.
301호.
We've received a report that some residents
우리는 보고서를 받았습니다 일부 주민들은
climbed the wall after curfew last night.
어젯밤 통금 시간 이후에 벽에 올랐어요.
-Pardon? -Us?
-뭐라고요? -우리를?
-It wasn't us. -Really?
- 우리가 아니었어요. -정말?
Where's Mommy?
엄마는 어디 계시나요?
She'll be here soon. Let's wait for her together.
그녀는 곧 여기에 올 것이다. 그녀를 함께 기다리자.
I'm not kicking you out because I don't like you.
나는 당신을 쫓아내는 것이 아닙니다 나는 당신을 좋아하지 않기 때문에.
We have rules we must follow at the dorms,
기숙사에서는 지켜야 할 규칙이 있는데,
and adults have circumstances they can't talk about.
어른들도 사정이 있어서 그들은 이야기할 수 없습니다.
I hope you can understand.
나는 당신이 이해할 수 있기를 바랍니다.
Please take good care of my mommy, ma'am.
우리 엄마를 잘 돌봐주세요, 아가씨.
"Ma'am"?
"부인"?
Bom!
봄!
Mommy!
엄마!
Weren't you scared? Are you okay?
두렵지 않았나요? 괜찮으세요?
-You didn't get hurt, did you? -No.
-다치진 않았지? -아니요.
-You must be hungry. -Yeah.
-배가 고프겠군요. -응.
What should we have for breakfast?
아침 식사로 무엇을 먹어야 할까요?
-I want jelly. -Oh yeah?
-젤리를 원해요. -아 그래요?
Shall we have some jelly then?
그럼 젤리라도 먹을까?
Let's go and get some.
가서 좀 사오자.
EPISODE 5: READY OR NOT, HERE I COME
에피소드 5: 준비됐든 아니든, 내가 간다
Listen,
들어봐,
having to deal with outsiders who have a distorted view of our company…
외부인을 상대해야 한다 우리 회사에 대해 왜곡된 시각을 갖고 있는 사람…
It's so tiring.
너무 피곤해요.
When you're doing well, people get jealous and resentful, don't they?
당신이 잘 지내면 사람들은 질투하고 분개하지 않나요?
I, Oh Deok-gyu, am a man of simple desires.
나 오덕규 나는 단순한 욕망을 가진 사람이다.
My only wish is to lay solid groundwork
나의 유일한 소망은 탄탄한 기초를 다지는 것
and polish it until it shines for when Albert inherits the company.
빛날 때까지 닦으세요. Albert가 회사를 상속받을 때를 위해.
You know?
알잖아?
For that to happen,
그런 일이 일어나려면,
I need your help, Mr. Nam. You get me?
남 선생님의 도움이 필요해요. 이해가 가시나요?
I'm at your service whenever, sir.
언제든지 도와드리겠습니다.
Whenever.
언제든지.
Is that so?
그렇습니까?
Let's have a drink. Cheers.
한잔하자. 건배.
-Thank you, sir. -Drink.
- 고마워요 선생님. -마시다.
So,
그래서,
have you got any news for me?
나한테 전할 소식 있어?
I need to present the chairman with something ironclad.
회장님을 소개해야 해요 철갑같은 뭔가로.
-Actually, sir… -Yeah?
-사실 선생님... -응?
There's a rumor that we've planted a spy in Hanmin.
소문이 있어요 우리가 한민에 스파이를 심었다는 것.
-A spy? -Yes.
- 스파이요? -예.
-You mean an infiltrator? -Yes, that's right.
-침입자 말이에요? -네, 맞습니다.
There's no way that President Kang was working alone
방법이 없어요 강 대표가 혼자 일하고 있었다고
to blow the whistle on the company.
회사에 휘파람을 불려고요.
So who is it?
그럼 누구죠?
How would I know?
내가 어떻게 알 수 있나요?
Sir, I've got news.
선생님, 소식이 있어요.
Yesterday,
어제,
I managed to acquire some intel from a trustworthy source at the FSS.
정보를 좀 얻었네요 FSS의 신뢰할 수 있는 출처에서 나온 것입니다.
Get to the point already.
이미 요점을 파악하세요.
Right.
오른쪽.
I heard
나는 들었다
there is an infiltrator in our company who helped President Kang
우리 회사에 침입자가 있다 강회장을 도와준 사람
prepare to blow the whistle.
휘파람을 불 준비를 하세요.
An infiltrator?
침입자?
That's right.
좋아요.
Well, I guess with the prosecutor's probe dropped
글쎄요 검찰 수사가 기각되면서
and President Kang's accident,
그리고 강회장의 사고,
they may have already left the company, but…
그들은 가지고 있을 수도 있다 이미 회사를 떠났지만…
We do have a way
우리에겐 방법이 있어요
to confirm it.
그것을 확인하기 위해.
Did you look into it?
조사해 보셨나요?
The employees President Kang had the most contact with before the accident.
강사장이 가지고 있던 직원들 사고 전 가장 많이 접촉한 사람.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
From January 1st, 1997,
1997년 1월 1일부터,
until July 21st, the day before the accident,
7월 21일까지, 사고 전날,
he frequently met with three employees in his office.
그는 자주 만났다 그의 사무실에는 세 명의 직원이 있었습니다.
Mr. So Gyeong-dong of Trading,
무역부 소경동님,
Mr. Bang Jin-mok of Risk Management,
리스크관리팀 방진목님,
and Mr. Cha Jung-il of Research.
그리고 차정일 연구위원님.
So-Bang-Cha.
소방차.
SO-BANG-CHA
소방차
WHISTLEBLOWER = INFILTRATOR
내부 고발자 = 침입자
They're our three candidates then.
그렇다면 그들은 우리의 세 후보입니다.
This should be kept top secret.
이는 일급 비밀로 유지되어야 합니다.
When it comes to weeds,
잡초의 경우,
you must pull them out by the roots
뿌리부터 뽑아내야 해요
and burn them to a crisp.
그리고 바삭바삭하게 태워주세요.
If you don't,
그렇지 않으면,
they will only grow back and ruin the whole field.
그들은 다시 자랄 것이다 들판 전체를 망쳐 놓을 것이다.
Executive Director Oh.
오 전무이사.
I'll entrust you with the weeding.
잡초 제거는 당신에게 맡기겠습니다.
I'll make them disappear without a trace, sir.
내가 그것들을 사라지게 할게요 흔적도 없이요, 선생님.
PERSONAL DETAILS
개인정보
The remaining Yehppee candidates now are Bang Jin-mok and Cha Jung-il.
이제 남은 Yehppee 후보는 방진목과 차정일.
I really hope it isn't Cha.
정말 차씨가 아니길 바라요.
Who said you could take away my computer?
누가 내 컴퓨터를 가져가도 된다고 했나요?
You're making a big mistake right now.
당신은 지금 큰 실수를 하고 있습니다.
At least tell me why you're doing this.
적어도 왜 이런 짓을 하는지는 말해주세요.
Don't just stand there!
거기 그냥 서 있지 마세요!
Hey, wait.
잠깐만요.
You can't take that.
당신은 그것을 받아들일 수 없습니다.
-Sir, wait. Hold on. -Just a moment.
- 선생님, 잠깐만요. 기다리다. - 잠시만요.
-Hold on a second. -Sir, you can't.
-잠깐만요. - 선생님, 그러면 안 돼요.
Damn it!
젠장!
Why is the Audit Division here?
감사부가 왜 여기에 있나요?
The Audit Division?
감사부서요?
Should we get closer for a better view?
더 잘 보려면 좀 더 가까이 다가가야 할까요?
-Seriously? -Come on.
-진지하게? -어서 해봐요.
What? This has nothing to do with us.
무엇? 이것은 우리와 아무 관련이 없습니다.
Take the computers, files, and everything else.
컴퓨터, 파일, 그리고 그 밖의 모든 것.
Take everything and leave nothing behind.
모든 것을 취하고 아무것도 남기지 마십시오.
-Yes, sir.
- 네, 선생님.
This is our office.
이곳은 우리 사무실입니다.
At least state your business.
최소한 귀하의 사업을 명시하십시오.
An internal audit into Mr. Bang Jin-mok has been launched.
내부 감사 방진목씨가 취임하였습니다.
You'll be cooperating.
당신은 협력할 것입니다.
Word of the internal audit at the head office
내부 감사의 말씀 본사에서
has even spread to the regional branches.
지역 지사까지 확산됐다.
If it's So-Bang-Cha, they must've gone to Trading too.
소방차라면, 그들도 트레이딩에 갔나 봐요.
These men in black suits rushed in,
검은 양복을 입은 남자들이 달려들었고,
and they cleaned us out in a flash.
그리고 그들은 순식간에 우리를 청소했습니다.
It was really scary.
정말 무서웠어요.
Did they say why they were taking it? Maybe some sort of an allegation?
왜 복용하는지 말했나요? 일종의 주장이 아닐까요?
By the way, what's an "infiltrator"?
그런데 "침입자"란 무엇입니까?
It's a term that refers to someone
누군가를 지칭하는 용어입니다.
who secretly invades an organization and operates covertly
비밀리에 조직에 침입한 사람 그리고 은밀하게 활동한다
to achieve a specific goal.
특정 목표를 달성하기 위해.
In English, they call it a "spy."
영어로는 '스파이'라고 합니다.
I see. A spy.
알겠어요. 스파이.
Who mentioned an infiltrator and when did you hear it?
누가 침입자를 언급했나 그리고 언제 들었어?
I heard it in the conference room after that whole mess.
회의실에서 들었어 그 엉망진창 이후.
I mean, we're nobodies, so they can treat us however,
즉, 우리는 아무 것도 아닌 존재입니다. 하지만 그들이 우리를 치료할 수 있도록
but you don't deserve this at all, Mr. So.
하지만 당신은 그럴 자격이 전혀 없습니다, 소 씨.
I don't deserve it, either.
나도 그럴 자격이 없어요.
It appears the chairman believes
회장님은 그렇게 믿고 있는 것 같습니다.
that there's an infiltrator among the three of us.
침입자가 있다는 걸 우리 셋 중.
What?
무엇?
What infiltrator?
무슨 침입자?
The whistleblower who exposed
폭로한 제보자
Hanmin's slush fund.
한민 비자금.
CONFERENCE ROOM
회의실
SO-BANG-CHA
소방차
INFILTRATOR CANDIDATES = YEHPPEE CANDIDATES
침입자 후보자 = 예피 후보
That explains it.
그것은 그것을 설명합니다.
What does it explain?
그것은 무엇을 설명합니까?
Do you know something?
당신은 뭔가를 알고 있나요?
The chairman's office
회장실
asked me to deliver the late President Kang's schedule.
나한테 배달해달라고 했어 고 강 회장의 일정.
I had to dig it back out of the scrap-paper bin.
다시 파헤쳐야 했어요 스크랩 종이 통의.
3RD QUARTER SCHEDULE
3분기 일정
Found it.
찾았습니다.
What? Why is it empty?
무엇? 왜 비어 있나요?
I went through hell to open that drawer that night.
나는 지옥을 겪었다 그날 밤 그 서랍을 열려고.
Seriously? It was in the scrap-paper bin?
진지하게? 휴지통에 있었나요?
Gosh, this is like a purge straight out of a historical drama.
맙소사, 이건 마치 퍼지 같아 바로 역사드라마에서 나온 것 같다.
Purge time…
퍼지 시간…
Do you think she's dating someone?
그 사람이 누군가와 데이트하고 있는 것 같나요?
Look at how spoiled she is.
그녀가 얼마나 버릇없었는지 보세요.
She's way too young to have a cellphone.
그녀는 휴대폰을 갖고 있기에는 너무 어리다.
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
She's still very young, so her parents probably got it for her.
그녀는 아직 아주 어려요. 그래서 그녀의 부모님이 아마도 그녀를 위해 그것을 얻었을 것입니다.
You're too soft-hearted.
당신은 마음이 너무 여린군요.
Why would you defend her?
왜 그녀를 변호하겠습니까?
I heard your company's internal audit team is on the move.
귀사 내부감사팀의 말을 들었습니다 이동 중입니다.
It's not my company.
내 회사가 아니거든요.
The higher-ups are looking for the whistleblower.
윗사람들은 제보자를 찾고 있습니다.
They're looking for Yehppee.
그들은 예피를 찾고 있어요.
I heard they detained the So-Bang-Cha trio.
그들이 구금됐다고 들었어 소방차 트리오.
See, kid? Didn't I tell you?
알겠어, 꼬마야? 내가 말하지 않았나요?
It's exactly as outlined in the X-file.
X-file에 설명된 대로입니다.
We must find out who Yehppee is first
먼저 Yehppee가 누구인지 알아내야 합니다.
before the evidence is destroyed.
증거가 인멸되기 전에.
And what about the favor I asked you for last time?
그리고 호의는 어떻습니까? 지난번에 제가 물었지요?
I'm working on it right now.
지금 작업 중이에요.
Just look at what you have me doing.
당신이 나에게 무엇을 하게 하는지 한번 보세요.
I've been on it for days, and I haven't even had dinner yet.
나는 며칠 동안 그 일을 해왔습니다. 그리고 아직 저녁도 안 먹었는데.
I can't believe I'm almost sixty and folding paper cranes.
내 나이 거의 예순이라니 믿을 수 없어 그리고 접는 종이학.
I can barely see, and my hands tremble.
앞이 잘 보이지 않고 손이 떨립니다.
How am I ever going to fold 1,000 of them?
1,000개를 어떻게 접을 수 있나요?
Yet
아직
I continue to fold,
계속해서 접고,
desperately praying that we find Yehppee first…
필사적으로 기도하다 예피를 먼저 찾으라고…
with every crane.
모든 크레인과 함께.
Let there be hope.
희망을 가지십시오.
I appreciate it.
감사합니다.
YEOUIDO PIRATES
여의도 파이리츠
COMMUNITY DISCUSSION BOARD
커뮤니티 토론 게시판
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
SEARCHING…
검색 중…
Questions about Hanmin's internal audit?
한민의 내부감사에 대해 질문이 있으신가요?
Ask away.
멀리 물어보세요.
They're even looking into work hours records.
그들은 심지어 조사 중이야 근무 시간 기록.
ANY SPECIFIC DATE?
구체적인 날짜가 있나요?
July 21, 1997.
1997년 7월 21일.
July 21st…
7월 21일…
Are you Yehppee?
당신은 Yehppee입니까?
That was the day before President Kang's accident.
그날이었어 강회장 사고 전.
It's the day I met him by the Han River.
한강에서 그를 만난 날이다.
BANG JIN-MOK
방진목
SEARCHING…
검색 중…
"The mutiny of the century…"
"세기의 반란…"
THE MUTINY OF THE CENTURY!
세기의 반란!
"The lowborn servant boy who dared to attack the crown prince of Hanmin…"
"감히 그런 짓을 한 천한 하인 소년 한민세자를 공격하려고…"
Wait, Mr. Bang!
잠깐만요, 뱅 씨!
-Let go of me! -What's up with you today?
-나를 놔줘! -오늘 무슨 일 있어?
Damn it.
젠장.
Aren't you so amazing?
정말 놀랍지 않나요?
You show up with a whole posse,
당신은 전체 병력을 가지고 나타나요.
the PR Division photographer, and even the chief of staff galore.
홍보부문 사진작가님, 심지어 참모총장까지.
Hey.
여기요.
You crash a staff dinner, put on a humble act,
당신은 직원 저녁 식사를 망쳤습니다. 겸손한 행동을 취하라.
and for the first time ever, gobble up some cheap pork belly and soju.
그리고 처음으로, 값싼 삼겹살과 소주를 먹어보세요.
And you call that "connecting with your employees"?
그리고 당신은 그렇게 부르죠 "직원들과의 연결"?
Hey, Bang Jin-mok.
안녕하세요, 방진목님.
You ate the most out of everyone.
당신은 누구보다도 가장 많이 먹었습니다.
Oh, have you been keeping track?
아, 계속 추적하고 있었나요?
You must get that pettiness from your father.
그 사소함을 얻어야 해 당신의 아버지로부터.
But then again,
그런데 또,
you wouldn't have a job if you weren't the chairman's son.
당신은 직업이 없을 것입니다 회장님 아들 아니었으면.
You act like I signed up to be his son.
당신은 내가 그의 아들이 되기로 약속한 것처럼 행동합니다.
You're the one who does all his dirty work.
당신이 바로 그 사람이에요 더러운 일을 다 하는 사람.
Isn't that how you keep your job?
그게 직업을 유지하는 방법 아닌가요?
What was that, you punk?
그게 뭐였지, 이 새끼야?
What?
무엇?
Even with titles aside, you're no match for me.
제목을 떠나도, 당신은 나와 일치하지 않습니다.
Also, I'm one whole year older than you.
게다가 나는 당신보다 한 살 더 많아요.
Watch your tone, you damn prick.
말투 조심해, 이 빌어먹을 놈아.
That's bullshit. We started college the same year!
그건 헛소리야. 우리는 같은 해에 대학을 시작했습니다!
Who cares? We're only the same age on the lunar calendar.
누가 신경쓰나요? 우리는 단지 같은 나이입니다 음력에.
What a petty little bastard.
정말 하찮은 놈이군요.
Whip out your ID. Go on.
신분증을 꺼내세요. 계속하세요.
You want me to whip it out?
내가 채찍질해 주기를 바라나요?
You got it.
당신은 그것을 얻었다.
Sure, I'll whip it out for you. Here.
물론이죠. 제가 대신 만들어 드릴게요. 여기.
There you go, punk.
됐어, 펑크.
Mr. Bang! Please try to calm down.
뱅 씨! 진정해 보세요.
I whipped one out for you. What now?
나는 당신을 위해 하나를 채찍질했습니다. 지금은 무엇입니까?
I whipped one out for His Excellency, the great chairman's son.
나는 각하를 위해 하나를 채찍질했습니다. 위대한 회장의 아들.
You did whip something there.
당신은 거기에서 뭔가를 채찍질했습니다.
What now?
지금은 무엇입니까?
Fine. Mr. Bang.
괜찮은. 방씨.
I'll go for the throat, you punk!
목구멍으로 갈게, 이 새끼야!
Hey!
여기요!
-Let go of me. -Hey, punk. You let go first.
-나를 놓아주세요. -안녕, 펑크. 당신이 먼저 놓아주세요.
-You're going to rip my skin off. -You'd better let go.
- 넌 내 피부를 찢어버릴 거야. - 놔두는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Damn it!
젠장!
-Come here, you. -Let go.
- 이리 오세요. - 놔.
Look at you go.
가는 것 좀 봐.
-You'd better let go. -Mr. Bang, please stop.
- 놔두는 게 좋을 것 같아요. -씨. 뱅, 그만둬주세요.
-You!
-너!
-Unbelievable. -Will you look at this?
-믿을 수 없는. - 이것 좀 봐줄래?
Let go.
가자.
-You let go. -You let go first.
- 놔두세요. -당신이 먼저 놔주세요.
Let go on the count of three.
셋을 센다.
-One, two. -Two.
- 하나, 둘. -둘.
-Three.
-삼.
-Unbelievable. -You sneaky bastard.
-믿을 수 없는. - 이 교활한 놈아.
What am I going to do with you?
내가 당신을 어떻게 할 건가요?
Let go. I said, let go.
가자. 나는 놔두라고 말했다.
Who could President Kang have trusted with the ledger?
강 회장은 누가 그랬겠는가? 장부를 믿었나요?
It seems like he was surrounded by enemies.
그것은 것 같다 그는 적들에게 둘러싸여 있었습니다.
Bok-hee, did Mr. So also stop by the president's office on July 21st?
복희 씨, 소씨도 들렀나요? 7월 21일 대통령실?
Could you be more annoying?
더 짜증나게 할 수 있나요?
3RD QUARTER SCHEDULE
3분기 일정
Mr. So wasn't in that day.
그 날에는 Mr. So가 없었습니다.
He was absent.
그는 결석했습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Sleep tight.
푹 자요.
"The president called for Mr. So,
"대통령이 소씨를 불러서,
but he was absent from work."
그런데 그 사람 회사에 결근했어요."
President Kang definitely said the delivery would happen that day.
강 대표는 분명히 말했다. 그날 배달이 일어날 것입니다.
That leaves
그게 떠난다
Bang Jin-mok and Cha Jung-il.
방진목과 차정일.
BANG JIN-MOK
방진목
CHA JUNG-IL
차정일
BANG JIN-MOK, CHA JUNG-IL
방진목, 차정일
SO GYEONG-DONG
소경동
1997 INTERNAL AUDIT REPORT
1997년 내부 감사 보고서
Their computers, personal files, and call records
그들의 컴퓨터, 개인 파일, 통화 기록
were all reviewed.
모두 검토되었습니다.
However, we found no evidence
그러나 우리는 증거를 찾지 못했습니다
of any attempted whistleblowing.
내부 고발 시도에 대해.
Nothing?
아무것도 아님?
-Executive Director Oh! -Yes, sir.
- 전무이사 오! - 네, 선생님.
You stir up trouble with false intel?
거짓 정보로 문제를 일으키시나요?
You damn fool.
이 바보야.
Goddamn it.
젠장.
Ms. Song, get us some tea.
송 씨, 차 좀 주세요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Am I doing all this for my sake?
나는 이 모든 일을 나를 위해 하고 있는 걸까?
Focusing all your efforts on Albert's succession
모든 노력을 집중 알베르의 계승에 관하여
wouldn't be enough right now.
지금 당장은 충분하지 않을 것입니다.
Yet you keep going around proving just how much of a fool you are.
그런데도 계속 돌아다니잖아 당신이 얼마나 바보인지 증명해 보세요.
Imagine if I fell ill and couldn't return.
내가 아파서 돌아올 수 없다고 상상해 보세요.
You'd be up against Song Ju-ran and Choi In-ja.
당신은 반대 할 것입니다 송주란과 최인자.
How would you ever beat those two women?
그 두 여자를 어떻게 이길 수 있겠습니까?
If you could give me a little more time, I will dig even deeper.
나에게 조금만 더 시간을 주신다면, 나는 더 깊이 파고들 것이다.
That's exactly your problem.
그게 바로 당신의 문제입니다.
You tried doing it by the book.
당신은 책에 따라 그것을 시도했습니다.
Now, it's time to try bending the rules.
이제 규칙을 바꿔볼 차례입니다.
Back them into a corner.
구석으로 돌려보내세요.
The one with a guilty conscience
죄책감을 갖고 있는 사람
will step forward on his own.
스스로 앞으로 나아갈 것이다.
You have until this Saturday.
이번 토요일까지 시간이 있어요.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Leave it to me, sir.
저에게 맡겨주세요.
Do take care of yourself, sir.
몸 조심하세요 선생님.
Mr. Oh has been summoning Albert a lot recently, hasn't he?
오씨가 소환됐다 Albert는 최근에 많이 그랬죠, 그렇죠?
Swap out the recorder in that room too.
그 방에 있는 녹음기도 바꿔보세요.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
Mr. Cha.
차씨.
I've completed your daughter's paper-crane assignment.
내가 당신 딸의 일을 끝냈어요 종이학 할당.
She got dumped by her boyfriend yesterday,
그녀는 어제 남자친구에게 차버렸어요
so that's all useless now.
그러니 이제 그건 다 쓸모없어요.
Toss it!
던져라!
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
The company can't treat me like this.
회사에서는 나를 이렇게 대할 수 없다.
Before it leaves me out in the cold,
날 추위 속에 내버려두기 전에,
I'll leave it first.
먼저 두고 갈게요.
No.
아니요.
I'll leave it for another!
나는 그것을 다른 것을 위해 남겨 둘 것이다!
I hear Yeouido is even more barren
여의도가 더 황량하다고 하던데
than the Han River in the dead of winter.
한겨울의 한강보다.
Ever since the news hit Yeouido Pirates,
그 소식이 여의도해적단에 전해졌을 때부터
people have been calling to check in on me for the first time ever.
사람들이 전화를 했어요 처음으로 나에 대해 확인하려고.
You two are
너희 둘은
really innocent, right?
정말 결백한 거 맞죠?
Come on now.
지금 어서.
You're something else.
당신은 다른 사람입니다.
Enjoying the show?
쇼를 즐기고 있나요?
On a day like this, you should be enjoying your booze…
이런 날에는, 술을 즐겨야지...
on the company's dime.
회사 돈으로.
And the most important bit of news
그리고 가장 중요한 소식은
is that the internal audit has cleared So-Bang-Cha
그게 내부 감사야. 소방차를 클리어했습니다
of all charges and allegations.
모든 혐의와 혐의에 대해.
-That's hot off the press. -See.
-언론에서 정말 핫한 소식이네요. -보다.
Really? There's no infiltrator here?
정말? 여기 침입자는 없나요?
Were you hoping for one?
하나를 기대하고 있었나요?
How could I not be curious?
내가 어떻게 궁금하지 않을 수 있겠는가?
There's even a poll on Yeouido Pirates.
여의도 해적단에 대한 여론조사도 있습니다.
Listen, Mr. Bang.
들어보세요, 방 선생님.
I also read on Yeouido Pirates about the "Mutiny of the Century."
여의도 해적단에 대해서도 읽었습니다. '세기의 반란'에 대해.
Did it really happen?
정말 그런 일이 일어났나요?
Yes, it did.
네, 그랬어요.
This is the 101st time he's been asked that,
이번이 101번째다 그 사람이 그런 질문을 받았어요.
-myself included. -I see.
-나도 포함됐다. -알겠어요.
How did you not get fired after that?
그 후 어떻게 해고되지 않았나요?
I can answer that for you.
제가 대신 답변해드릴 수 있습니다.
I believe it was right before the 1988 Olympics.
나는 그랬다고 믿는다 1988년 올림픽 직전.
Hanmin ran into major trouble over accounting fraud allegations,
한민은 큰 고민에 빠졌다 분식회계 의혹에 대해
and the one who saved it
그리고 그걸 저장한 사람이
was none other than Manager Bang Jin-mok.
바로 방진목 감독이었다.
It was all him.
그 사람이 전부였습니다.
CONFERENCE ROOM AUTHORIZED PERSONNEL ONLY
회의실 승인된 직원만 가능
Our backs were against the wall and we were about to be gutted,
우리 등은 벽에 기대어 있었어 그리고 우리는 파멸 직전이었는데,
but he clawed out a lifeline.
하지만 그는 생명줄을 뽑아냈습니다.
You see, he's a whiz when it comes to numbers.
알다시피, 그는 천재야 숫자에 관해서라면.
He's good at sprucing them up.
그는 그것들을 꾸미는 데 능숙합니다.
Hanmin made sure the numbers added up before sending them.
한민이가 확실했어 숫자를 보내기 전에 합산되었습니다.
They can't do that.
그들은 그렇게 할 수 없습니다.
Inflated financials, cooked books,
부풀려진 금융, 조리된 책,
and audit report wordplay.
그리고 감사 보고서 말장난.
It's all unacceptable.
그것은 모두 용납될 수 없습니다.
But then again, who knows?
그런데 또 누가 알겠어요?
You never really know what's in someone's heart.
넌 정말 모르지 누군가의 마음 속에 무엇이 있는지.
Cha Jung-il, it sounds like you have doubts about me.
차정일 그런거같아 당신은 나에 대해 의심을 가지고 있습니다.
Me, doubt the key asset in the shadows?
나, 그림자 속의 핵심 자산이 의심되는가?
Oh, I'd never dare.
아, 감히 그럴 수가 없어요.
-Please eat up. -Sure.
- 맛있게 드세요. -확신하는.
Did you make up with President Kang afterward?
화장했니? 그다음에 강회장이랑?
No.
아니요.
They were ready to start a fight every time they saw each other.
그들은 싸움을 시작할 준비가 되어 있었어요 서로를 볼 때마다.
Whenever he saw me, he called me the moneywasher.
그가 나를 볼 때마다, 그는 나를 돈세탁자라고 불렀습니다.
He mocked me for doing what his father told me to do.
그 사람은 내가 하는 짓을 비웃었어 그의 아버지가 나에게 하라고 하신 일.
Does this mean Bang is out of the running for Yehppee?
이것이 의미하는 바는 무엇입니까? Bang은 Yehppee 출마에서 제외되었나요?
BANG IS OUT?
뱅이 나갔어?
Honestly, if it weren't for Mr. So and me,
솔직히 소씨와 제가 아니었다면
you wouldn't have survived in here.
당신은 여기서 살아남지 못했을 거예요.
Man, I miss Myeong-hwi.
아, 명휘 보고싶다.
Let's have a drink.
한잔하자.
Mr. Cha, did you ever get into a fight with President Kang?
차씨, 그런 적 있나요? 강회장이랑 싸웠어?
Come on now.
지금 어서.
They were high school classmates, college alumni,
고등학교 동창이었는데, 대학 졸업생,
and even enlisted in the military together.
그리고 심지어 입대했다 군대에서 함께.
A fight between us?
우리 사이에 싸움이요?
Never!
절대!
We have never once fought.
우리는 한 번도 싸운 적이 없습니다.
SEOUL CITY DORMITORY FOR SINGLE FEMALE WORKERS
서울시립기숙사 미혼 여성 근로자를 위한
Jang-mi has another team dinner tonight.
장미는 오늘 밤에도 팀 저녁 식사를 합니다.
The Curse of the Site Inspector Ghost.
사이트 조사관 유령의 저주.
There was a maiden ghost who once dreamt of owning her own place in Seoul.
한때 꿈을 꾸던 처녀귀신이 있었어요 서울에 자신의 집을 소유하는 것.
Even after death,
죽은 뒤에도,
her resentment drove her to wander through every apartment building in Seoul.
그녀의 분노가 그녀를 방황하게 만들었다. 서울의 모든 아파트를 통해
That's when…
그때는…
Mi-sook.
미숙.
Turn the TV off.
TV를 끄세요.
Maybe it's Jang-mi?
아마도 장미인가?
Why would she knock when she has the keys?
열쇠를 갖고 있는데 왜 노크를 하겠는가?
Right.
오른쪽.
It must be the RA, right?
RA겠죠?
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
You guys need to come with me.
너희들은 나와 함께 가야 해.
Mommy.
엄마.
Bom.
봄.
How did you get here?
어떻게 여기까지 왔나요?
You're soaking wet. Are you okay?
흠뻑 젖어 있군요. 괜찮으세요?
What are you doing here?
여기서 뭐하는거야?
Bom, let's go inside. Come on.
봄아, 안으로 들어가자. 어서 해봐요.
Let's go inside.
안으로 들어가자.
Kim Bom.
김봄.
How could you even think of coming here by yourself?
어떻게 생각을 할 수가 있어? 여기 혼자 온다고?
Didn't I tell you to stay put at the children's home?
내가 가만히 있으라고 말하지 않았어? 아이들 집에서?
I told you I'd be back for you if you behaved there.
내가 당신을 위해 돌아올 거라고 말했어요 당신이 거기에서 행동했다면.
Why didn't you do as I said?
왜 내가 말한 대로 하지 않았나요?
Are you going to be a bad girl?
나쁜 여자가 될 건가요?
You promised you'd behave.
당신은 행동하겠다고 약속했습니다.
Why would you do this?
왜 이런 일을 하시겠습니까?
Hey, keep it down.
이봐, 조용히 해라.
We'll all be kicked out if the RA catches us!
우리 다 쫓겨날 거야 RA가 우리를 잡으면!
Hey, Jang-mi.
안녕, 장미야.
I'm back.
나는 돌아왔다.
Don't worry, I'll clean all this up.
걱정하지 마세요. 제가 다 정리할게요.
Go on inside.
안으로 들어가세요.
So you know enough to fear Hong Jang-mi.
그러니 홍장미를 두려워할 만큼 알고 계시군요.
Mr. Cha.
차씨.
Why didn't the auditors take his laptop?
감사관은 왜 그의 노트북을 가져가지 않았나요?
His laptop?
그의 노트북?
The truth is, he's clueless about technology.
진실은, 그는 기술에 대해 아무것도 모릅니다.
In fact, I was setting up his laptop that day.
사실 제가 준비하고 있던 건 그날 그의 노트북.
What do you think you're doing?
지금 뭐하고 있는 것 같나요?
-Take everything. -Sir, please try to calm down.
- 다 가져가세요. - 선생님, 진정 좀 해주세요.
Damn it.
젠장.
The auditors simply didn't know because it was his personal laptop.
감사원들은 전혀 몰랐어요 왜냐하면 그것은 그의 개인 노트북이었기 때문입니다.
For Mr. Cha, a laptop is no different from an expensive belt.
차씨에게 노트북도 다르지 않다 값비싼 벨트에서.
Thank you for calling. You've reached Risk Management.
전화해주셔서 감사합니다. 위험 관리에 도달했습니다.
Interesting timing, sir.
타이밍이 흥미롭습니다.
No.
아니요.
I'm on my way.
지금 가는 중이에요.
See?
보다?
He's even asking for help with his computer now.
그리곤 도움을 요청한다 지금 그의 컴퓨터로.
Well, when it comes to computers,
뭐, 컴퓨터에 관해서라면,
you're the best in this building…
당신은 이 건물에서 최고예요…
I mean, in all of Yeouido, and no one even comes close.
여의도 전역에서요. 그리고 아무도 가까이 오지도 않습니다.
Well, yes.
그렇죠.
Yes, right. Feel free to ask any questions.
예, 그렇죠. 궁금한 점이 있으면 언제든지 문의하세요.
Is there any chance
기회가 있나요?
you know how to hack too?
너도 해킹할 줄 알아?
Hack?
마구 자르기?
Let's pause for a second.
잠시 멈춰보자.
Lee Yong-gi is one of the seven who developed cyber banking
이용기는 7인 중 한 명이다. 사이버뱅킹을 개발한 사람
and a former white-hat hacker.
그리고 전직 화이트 해커였습니다.
That's asking for too much, right?
너무 많은 것을 요구하는 거죠?
Yeah, that's too much.
응, 그건 너무해.
No need to strain yourself.
긴장할 필요가 없습니다.
"Strain"?
"부담"?
Did you say, "strain"?
"긴장"이라고 말했나요?
Yeah, no idea.
응, 모르겠어.
HACKING IN PROGRESS…
해킹 진행 중…
HACKING COMPLETE!
해킹이 완료되었습니다!
So you're saying that this is Mr. Cha's laptop, right?
그래서 당신이 말하는 것은 이거 차 선생님 노트북 맞죠?
You're so amazing.
당신은 정말 대단해요.
That's nothing.
그건 아무것도 아닙니다.
Now that we've seen it, we should turn it--
이제 우리는 그것을 보았습니다. 돌려야 해
Wait.
잠깐만요.
Would you like this?
이것을 원하십니까?
But this is so precious.
하지만 이것은 너무나 소중한 것입니다.
They say your wish comes true if you fold 1,000 paper cranes.
소원이 이루어진다고 하네요 종이학 1000개를 접으면
Mr. Cha had me make them, so I'm not sure about the wishes.
차 선생님께서 만들어 주셨는데, 그래서 나는 소망에 대해 확신하지 못합니다.
Still, you made them with your own hands.
그래도 직접 손으로 만드셨어요.
Well, sort of.
글쎄요.
They are handmade, I guess.
제 생각엔 수제인 것 같아요.
SNAPSHOTS FROM AROUND THE WORLD
전 세계의 스냅샷
Wow.
와우.
Don't look, Ms. Hong.
보지 마세요, 홍 선생님.
Is he insane?
그 사람 미쳤나요?
Adult content at work?
직장에서 성인용 콘텐츠를 사용하시나요?
What a pervert.
정말 변태네요.
FINANCIAL STRATEGY
재무 전략
"Financial Strategy"?
"재무 전략"?
"19970529"?
"19970529"?
It sounds like a date.
데이트하는 것 같군요.
Why did you ask to see me?
왜 나한테 만나자고 했어?
Aren't you the busiest person at the company these days?
당신은 가장 바쁜 사람이 아닌가? 요즘 회사에서?
Surely, I couldn't be busier than you.
물론, 나는 당신보다 더 바쁠 수 없습니다.
President Kang is constantly calling you in
강 대표는 끊임없이 당신을 부르고 있어요
over the slush fund probe.
비자금 조사에 대해.
I'm just doing my job for the company, after all.
난 그냥 내 일을 하고 있을 뿐이야 결국 회사를 위해서죠.
What if
만약에
the prosecutors come after the Outstanding Women Employees' Club?
검찰이 뒤따른다 우수여성직원클럽?
I doubt they're capable of thinking outside the box.
나는 그들이 할 수 있을지 의심스럽다. 상자 밖에서 생각하기.
For this incident…
이번 사건으로…
President Kang will take the fall.
강 대표는 가을을 맡을 것이다.
An arrest may be unavoidable for him.
그에게는 체포가 불가피할 수도 있다.
Does Myeong-hwi know this?
명휘도 이 사실을 알고 있나요?
It's what the chairman has decided.
위원장이 결정한 것입니다.
You just need to testify
증언만 하면 돼
that President Kang led the creation and management of the slush fund.
강 대표가 창작을 주도했다고 한다. 및 비자금 관리.
What are you saying?
무슨 말을 하는 거야?
Are you asking me…
나한테 묻는 거야?
to betray Myeong-hwi?
명휘를 배신하려고?
I heard your father-in-law's factory is
아버님 공장이 여기 있다고 들었는데
unable to cover its promissory notes.
약속어음을 다룰 수 없습니다.
At this rate,
이 속도로,
they'll go bankrupt in two weeks.
그 사람들은 2주 안에 파산할 거예요.
Not to mention, the Mapo apartment under your wife's name
말할 것도 없이, 아내 명의로 된 마포아파트
is about to go into foreclosure.
압류에 들어갈 예정이다.
The company can prevent both
회사에서는 두 가지 모두를 방지할 수 있습니다.
if you act in the company's interest.
회사의 이익을 위해 행동하는 경우.
I'll need an advance payment.
선불이 필요해요.
Please prepare the full amount
전액을 준비해 주세요
in cash within three days.
3일 이내에 현금으로.
So Cha was already working for Song.
그래서 차씨는 이미 송씨 밑에서 일하고 있었던 거다.
What happened today will stay just between us.
오늘 무슨 일이 있었나요? 우리 사이에만 머물 것입니다.
Of course.
물론.
I love secrets.
나는 비밀을 좋아합니다.
1997…
1997년…
0721?
0721?
Here's what I found on Hong Keum-bo.
홍금보에서 찾은 내용은 다음과 같습니다.
No employee by that name is currently on staff at the Jeonju branch of the FSS.
현재 해당 이름의 직원이 없습니다. 금감원 전주지사 직원입니다.
I've confirmed that she's on long-term leave from the head office.
그 사람이 출연한 걸 확인했어요 본사 장기퇴사.
There are no signs of anyone living in the apartment under her name in Seoul,
사람이 살고 있는 흔적은 전혀 없습니다 서울에 있는 그녀 이름의 아파트에서
and it's been a while since the security guard has seen her.
그리고 꽤 시간이 지났어 경비원이 그녀를 봤기 때문이다.
Look into her younger sister, Hong Jang-mi, as well.
그녀의 여동생을 들여다보세요. 홍장미도 그렇고.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Hong Keum-bo.
홍금보.
This can't all be a coincidence.
이것이 모두 우연일 수는 없습니다.
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
If the intel is wrong…
정보가 틀렸다면…
and we fail to flush out the infiltrator,
침입자를 쫓아내는데 실패하고,
we'll lose the chairman's trust.
회장님의 신뢰를 잃게 됩니다.
Don't worry.
괜찮아요.
Grandpa never trusted you to begin with.
할아버지는 처음부터 당신을 믿지 않으셨습니다.
Also, the Audit Division didn't find a single thing.
또한 감사부문은 단 하나도 찾지 못했습니다.
There's no spy here.
여기에는 스파이가 없습니다.
Then we'll need to make one.
그럼 하나 만들어야겠습니다.
That's how you and I
너와 내가 그러는 거야
will survive.
살아남을 것이다.
Come in.
들어오세요.
Sit.
앉아.
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
On July 21st,
7월 21일,
the day before President Kang's accident,
강 회장의 사고 전날,
what were you two up to?
너희 둘은 무슨 일을 했어?
I just happened to review the surveillance footage.
우연히 리뷰하게 됐는데 감시 영상.
Mr. Cha Jung-il, around 8 p.m. that day,
오후 8시쯤 차정일 씨. 그날,
you stopped by the president's office.
대통령 집무실에 들렀습니다.
And Mr. Bang,
그리고 방씨,
you conversed with President Kang in an elevator around 9 p.m.
강 회장님과 통화하셨는데요 오후 9시쯤 엘리베이터에서
That's not quite what you wrote in your statements to the Audit Division.
당신이 쓴 내용은 그게 아니네요 감사 부서에 제출한 진술서.
Did you both leave that out?
너희 둘 다 그걸 놔뒀어?
Both of you
너희 둘 다
will bring me evidence that proves you're innocent.
나에게 증거를 가져올 것이다 그것은 당신이 결백하다는 것을 증명합니다.
You have until noon tomorrow.
내일 정오까지 시간이 있어요.
I can't continue working with a traitor.
나는 배신자와 계속 일할 수 없습니다.
It's for Albert's sake as well.
그것도 알베르를 위해서다.
Man, that's bitter.
정말 씁쓸하네요.
THE NEXT DAY
다음날
Hello, this is Bang Jin-mok.
안녕하세요 방진목입니다.
Is it ready?
준비됐나요?
Thank you.
감사합니다.
Mr. Oh, what's going on?
아 씨, 무슨 일이에요?
It's my dad.
우리 아빠예요.
He summoned Bang and Cha
방과 차를 소환했다.
to demand evidence proving their innocence.
증거를 요구하다 그들의 결백을 증명합니다.
They had until noon today.
오늘 정오까지 시간이 있었어요.
Mr. Lee, let's have a smoke.
이 선생님, 담배 좀 피우세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
Enjoy.
즐기다.
REDIAL
재다이얼
Sangma Photo Studio.
상마사진관.
The primary beneficiary of the slush fund is you, Myeong-hwi!
주요 수혜자 비자금의 주인공은 명휘 당신이에요!
So that's why you sold me off?
그래서 나를 팔아넘긴 거요?
This is precisely why I can't trust you!
이것이 바로 내가 당신을 믿을 수 없는 이유입니다!
That's a recording from July 21st,
7월 21일의 녹음입니다.
the day before President Kang's accident.
강 회장의 사고 전날.
It's just as you heard.
그것은 당신이 들었던 그대로입니다.
Myeong-hwi
명휘
did not trust me.
나를 믿지 않았습니다.
Now,
지금,
that leaves Manager Bang Jin-mok.
방진목 감독이 떠난다.
COLOR FILM
컬러필름
Are you not headed to Mr. Oh's office?
오씨 사무실로 안 가시나요?
No, I'm off to see the chairman.
아니요, 회장님을 만나러 가겠습니다.
The chairman isn't someone just anyone can meet at will.
회장은 사람이 아니다 누구나 마음대로 만날 수 있어요.
COLOR FILM
컬러필름
I'll need to review that first.
먼저 그 점을 검토해 보아야겠습니다.
Cha Jung-il must've handed over the recording.
차정일이 넘겨줬나봐 녹음.
What could Bang Jin-mok have photos of?
방진목은 어떤 사진을 갖고 있을까?
Mr. Bang Jin-mok's order is ready.
방진목님의 주문이 준비되었습니다.
SANGMA COLOR PHOTO LAB
상마컬러사진연구소
Here are your photos.
여기 사진이 있습니다.
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
-감사합니다. -천만에요.
On the evening of July 21st, I ran into President Kang in the elevator
7월 21일 저녁, 엘리베이터에서 강회장과 마주쳤다
as I was heading home.
내가 집으로 향하던 중에.
He was on the phone.
그는 통화 중이었습니다.
Something about the conversation felt off, so I followed him.
대화 내용이 뭔가 기분이 나빴는데, 그래서 나는 그를 따라갔습니다.
Those are the photos I took then.
그때 찍은 사진들이에요.
And this woman?
그리고 이 여자는요?
I followed her and saw her enter the FSS building.
나는 그녀를 따랐다 그녀가 FSS 건물에 들어가는 것을 보았습니다.
Sir.
선생님.
I finally found the truth.
나는 마침내 진실을 찾았습니다.
Bang Jin-mok, that bastard…
방진목, 그 새끼...
I'm certain that Bang Jin-mok is the infiltrator.
나는 확신한다 방진목이 잠입자다.
I demanded the truth, and he failed to prove his innocence.
진실을 요구했지만 그리고 그는 자신의 결백을 증명하지 못했습니다.
He didn't show up because he had something to hide.
그는 나타나지 않았다 왜냐하면 그에게는 숨길 것이 있었기 때문입니다.
We must come down hard…
우리는 열심히 내려와야 해…
Manager Bang Jin-mok
방진목 과장
is not the spy.
스파이가 아닙니다.
Sir.
선생님.
How did you get that?
그걸 어떻게 얻었나요?
Why did Bang Jin-mok
방진목은 왜 그랬을까?
keep this under wraps until now?
지금까지 비밀로 해두셨나요?
President Kang passed away the very next day
강 회장 별세 바로 다음날
and with the prosecutor's investigation wrapping up,
그리고 검찰 수사로 마무리하고,
he simply didn't think to report it.
그는 단지 그것을 보고할 생각이 없었을 뿐입니다.
And what is this woman up to?
그리고 이 여자는 뭐하고 있는 걸까요?
Hong Keum-bo has been transferred to the Jeonju branch.
홍금보 이적 전주지점으로.
It's unlikely she'll return to the head office.
그녀가 돌아올 가능성은 거의 없습니다 본사로.
-Executive Director Oh. -Yes, sir.
-오 전무. - 네, 선생님.
I'm the one at fault for trusting you.
당신을 믿은 것은 나 자신의 잘못입니다.
You can't even break even, goddamn it.
심지어 손익분기점도 안 돼, 젠장.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
It ended with my father barking up the wrong tree.
아버지와 함께 끝났어요 잘못된 나무를 짖는 것.
So an internal audit was conducted
그래서 내부 감사를 실시했습니다.
to find the whistleblower involved
관련된 내부 고발자를 찾기 위해
in the investigation of Hanmin's slush fund.
조사 중 한민 비자금.
And President Kang Myeong-hwi was also involved in it.
그리고 강명휘 회장님 그 일에도 참여했습니다.
Maybe?
아마도?
You may leave.
떠날 수도 있습니다.
Hold on.
기다리다.
I heard my grandpa asked you to tutor me.
할아버지가 너한테 가르쳐 달라고 하셨다는 걸 들었어.
But it feels like I'm coaching you on all fronts, doesn't it?
근데 코칭하는 느낌이야 모든 면에서 그렇죠?
You're still here?
아직 여기 있나요?
That's why Hong Keum-bo snuck into this company,
그렇기 때문에 홍금보 이 회사에 몰래 들어가,
to find Hanmin's slush fund and the whistleblower.
한민의 비자금을 찾으러 그리고 제보자.
Seriously, soup with rice? This is so petty.
진심으로, 밥이 들어간 수프? 이건 너무 사소해요.
Mr. Oh treats me like I'm some bargain-bin pawn.
오씨가 나를 대접한다 마치 내가 헐값에 팔리는 졸개인 것처럼.
No, wait.
아니, 잠깐만요.
Maybe he's got a big wad of cash for me?
어쩌면 그 사람이 나한테 엄청난 현금을 갖고 있는 게 아닐까?
Jeez, I don't want to end up like the former team manager.
이런, 난 끝내고 싶지 않아 전 팀 매니저처럼요.
Hello, sir.
안녕하세요, 선생님.
I thought I'd be nice and feed you before I said this,
내가 친절하게 대해주고 먹여줄 줄 알았는데 내가 이 말을 하기 전에,
but now, I think even that would be a waste.
그런데 지금은 그런 생각도 들어요 낭비가 될 것입니다.
Hey.
여기요.
Do you know how utterly humiliated I was
내가 얼마나 굴욕을 느꼈는지 알아?
after I made moves based on your crappy intel?
내가 움직인 후 네 형편없는 정보를 바탕으로?
Why I ought to…
내가 그래야 하는 이유는…
Do not call me for a while. Got it?
당분간 전화하지 마세요. 알았어요?
Damn it.
젠장.
Unbelievable.
믿을 수 없는.
Is everyone working late tonight?
다들 오늘 밤 늦게까지 일하시나요?
I'm exhausted.
나는 지쳤다.
Seriously?
진지하게?
Who would look at this and know it was you?
누가 이걸 보겠는가 그게 당신인 줄 알아요?
Just go down to Yeouido Park,
여의도공원으로 내려가서
and you'll see tons of average-looking women like this.
그리고 당신은 수많은 것을 보게 될 것입니다 보통 외모의 여자들이 이런 걸 좋아해요.
Jeez.
이런.
Get it together, Hong Keum-bo!
힘내라 홍금보!
Bom.
봄.
Bom, what's wrong?
봄, 무슨 일이야?
Bom!
봄!
Hurry up.
서둘러요.
It's almost curfew.
거의 통행 금지 시간입니다.
Wait, I think that was Jang-mi.
잠깐만요, 장미였던 것 같아요.
It's almost midnight.
거의 자정이다.
Hurry up now. It's almost curfew.
지금 서둘러요. 거의 통행 금지 시간입니다.
I could've sworn that was Jang-mi.
나는 그 사람이 장미라고 맹세할 수 있었다.
Bom, are you in the bathroom?
봄아, 화장실에 있어?
Bom.
봄.
-Oh no. -What is it? Is Bom not there?
-안 돼. -이게 뭐죠? 봄은 없나요?
Oh no.
안 돼.
Bom?
봄?
Bom…
봄…
Doctor.
의사.
Are you not going to do a full checkup on this kid?
안 할 거야? 이 아이에 대한 종합 검진이요?
Oh, just a moment.
아, 잠시만요.
It's a cold-induced fever, so we prescribed fever reducers.
감기로 인한 발열입니다. 그래서 우리는 해열제를 처방했습니다.
-As her mother, you-- -I'm not her mother.
-그녀의 어머니로서 당신은-- -나는 그 사람 엄마가 아니야.
-Are you her guardian? -I'm not her guardian, either.
-당신이 그 사람의 보호자인가요? -나도 그 사람의 보호자가 아니야.
Then could we get your name as the person who brought her in?
그럼 당신의 이름을 알 수 있을까요? 그녀를 데려온 사람으로서?
It's Hong Keum…
홍금이다...
I mean, it's Hong Jang-mi.
바로 홍장미입니다.
Ma'am, where's my mommy?
부인, 우리 엄마는 어디 계시나요?
Ms. Hong.
홍 선생님.
Please contact her guardian first.
보호자에게 먼저 연락해주세요.
I will.
그럴게요.
Are you okay?
괜찮으세요?
I'm hungry.
배고파요.
You're hungry?
배고픈가요?
Bom!
봄!
What took you so long? I called ages ago.
왜 그렇게 오래 걸렸나요? 오래 전에 전화했어요.
The main gate was locked.
정문은 잠겨 있었습니다.
We climbed over the wall but there were no cabs.
우리는 벽을 넘어갔어 하지만 택시는 없었습니다.
Bom, are you okay?
봄, 괜찮아?
I'm okay, Mommy.
난 괜찮아요, 엄마.
She had a high fever of 38°C, but she's much better now.
38°C의 고열을 앓고 있었고, 하지만 지금은 훨씬 나아졌어요.
They said she can go home after the IV drip.
집에 갈 수 있다고 하더군요 IV 드립 후.
Now that you're here, I'll be off.
이제 당신이 여기 있으니 저는 이만 물러가겠습니다.
Wait, Jang-mi.
잠깐, 장미야.
We'll get demerit points if we go now.
지금 가면 벌점을 받을 거예요.
You're worried about me now after pulling this stunt?
너 지금 나 걱정하는구나 이 스턴트를 한 후에?
Nobody has time for sloppy lies.
아무도 엉성한 거짓말을 할 시간이 없습니다.
How could three adults not manage one kid?
어떻게 어른 세 명이 아이 한 명을 관리하지 못할 수 있겠습니까?
RESTRICTED AREA
제한 구역
Good morning, Ms. Song.
좋은 아침이에요, 송 씨.
No need.
필요하지 않습니다.
Thank you.
감사합니다.
It's me, Pil-beom.
나야, 필범.
What's this now?
지금 이게 뭐야?
Don't tell me you two were together all night.
나에게 말하지 마세요 너희 둘은 밤새도록 함께 있었어.
There you go with your nonsense again!
또 말도 안되는 소리를 하네!
Ms. Song, give us the room.
송 선생님, 방을 주세요.
Enjoy your meal.
식사를 즐기십시오.
Thanks.
감사해요.
Pil-beom.
필범.
You need to drink every drop of this.
이거 한 방울씩 다 마셔야 해요.
This is the detox juice that Hollywood actors drink.
디톡스 주스예요 헐리우드 배우들이 마시는 것.
Go on.
계속하세요.
Am I an actor?
나는 배우인가?
It's really tasty.
정말 맛있어요.
Seeing you come running here at the crack of dawn,
여기로 달려오는 걸 보니 새벽이 되자,
calling me by my name…
내 이름을 부르며…
You must need money again, don't you?
또 돈이 필요하겠네요, 그렇죠?
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
The truth is,
진실은,
I'm here to discuss President Shin as a potential son-in-law.
저는 신 회장에 대해 논의하기 위해 왔습니다. 잠재적인 사위로서.
What?
무엇?
I mean, he's handsome with a solid build, and educated enough.
내 말은, 그 사람은 탄탄한 체격에 잘생겼단 말이야. 그리고 충분히 교육받았어요.
I can totally picture him with our Nora.
나는 그가 우리 Nora와 함께 있는 모습을 완전히 상상할 수 있습니다.
If you can picture it, then I know it's a bust.
그림으로 그려볼 수 있다면, 그러면 난 그게 파산이라는 걸 알아요.
What? Bust?
무엇? 흉상?
Look.
바라보다.
He may look like some hotshot on the surface,
그 사람 좀 잘 생긴 사람처럼 보일 수도 있지 표면적으로,
but he's just a glorified puppet running things on behalf of the real boss.
하지만 그는 단지 영광스러운 꼭두각시일 뿐이야 실제 상사를 대신하여 일을 운영합니다.
Muppet?
머펫?
He's no muppet. He's in excellent shape.
그는 머펫이 아닙니다. 그는 몸매가 아주 좋습니다.
Goodness gracious.
맙소사.
When the time comes,
때가 되면,
I'll have Ms. Song find Nora a suitable partner.
송씨에게 노라를 찾게 할게요 적합한 파트너.
So you just stay out of it.
그러니 당신은 그것에서 벗어나십시오.
But I'm her mother. Why would I let Ms. Song do that?
하지만 나는 그 사람의 어머니예요. 내가 왜 송씨에게 그런 일을 시키겠는가?
Don't argue with me, woman!
나랑 논쟁하지 마세요, 아가씨!
Come on, Pil-beom.
자, 필범.
Honey.
꿀.
-"Honey"? -Come on, honey.
-"꿀"? -어서, 얘야.
-Fine, just don't-- -Stop it.
-좋아요, 그러지 마세요-- - 그만해요.
Go on.
계속하세요.
Drink it up, to the very last drop.
마지막 한 방울까지 다 마셔보세요.
There you go. Drink it all.
됐어요. 다 마셔라.
So when's the blind date with the chairman's daughter?
그럼 소개팅은 언제야? 회장 딸이랑?
Next week.
다음 주.
I didn't see that coming.
나는 그것이 오는 것을 보지 못했습니다.
I thought you'd be repulsed.
나는 당신이 거절 당할 것이라고 생각했습니다.
Networks and connections are all that matter in Korean society.
네트워크 및 연결 한국 사회에서는 그게 전부다.
You couldn't buy this connection.
이 연결을 구입할 수 없습니다.
The chairman sees me as a figurehead president,
회장님이 저를 보셨어요 일인자 대통령으로서,
a sort of tutor for his grandson.
그의 손자를위한 일종의 가정교사.
All his important decisions
그의 모든 중요한 결정
are made in closed-door meetings with his chief of staff.
비공개 회의로 이루어진다 그의 비서실장과 함께.
I'd need to be a potential son-in-law
잠재적인 사위가 되어야 할 텐데
for him to let his guard down.
그가 경계심을 풀도록.
Okay.
좋아요.
We need you in those closed-door meetings
비공개 회의에는 여러분이 필요합니다
if we want to hit the jackpot.
대박을 터뜨리고 싶다면.
A crisis is inevitable.
위기는 불가피하다.
We need to seize the opportunity.
우리는 기회를 포착해야 합니다.
Here you go.
여기요.
Here's to another rewarding day,
오늘도 보람찬 하루 되세요
respectively.
각각.
Sir, here's the final report on the proposed
선생님, 최종 보고서입니다 제안에
internal system improvements.
내부 시스템 개선.
INTERNAL SYSTEM ENHANCEMENT PROPOSAL BLOCKING OUT-OF-RANGE ORDERS
내부 시스템 개선 제안 범위를 벗어난 주문 차단
In Hanmin's current trading system,
한민의 현행 트레이딩 시스템에서는
orders placed by traders are sent straight to the Korea Exchange.
거래자가 주문한 내용이 전송됩니다. 바로 한국거래소로 갑니다.
Under our proposed safeguards, orders that exceed 8% of the market price
우리가 제안한 보호 조치에 따라, 시장 가격의 8%를 초과하는 주문
will be flagged as erroneous,
오류로 표시됩니다.
blocked internally, and automatically marked as unfilled.
내부적으로 차단되었으며, 자동으로 채워지지 않은 것으로 표시됩니다.
We shut it down if it's suspicious in the slightest.
우리는 그것을 종료했습니다 조금이라도 의심스럽다면.
It'll be a trap with no escape.
탈출할 수 없는 함정이 될 것이다.
Nice!
멋진!
Ms. Hong, you'll come with me.
홍 선생님, 저와 함께 가세요.
To where?
어디로?
The president's office.
대통령 집무실.
-Me? -Yes.
-나? -예.
Why would I?
내가 왜 그럴까요?
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
SUMMARY OF KEY ENHANCEMENTS
주요 개선 사항 요약
5. PROJECTED BENEFITS 6. ADDITIONAL NOTES
5. 예상 이익 6. 추가 참고사항
Well done, Risk Management Division.
수고하셨습니다, 리스크 관리 부서.
I must say
나는 말해야 한다
this was all thanks to Ms. Hong's generous guidance and support.
이게 다 홍 선생님 덕분이에요. 아낌없는 지도와 지원.
You mean Ms. Hong Jang-mi?
홍장미 선생님 말씀이신가요?
Yes, sir.
네, 선생님.
Truth be told,
사실대로 말하면,
we did have some dead weight around.
우리 주변에는 약간의 체중이있었습니다.
But it was made possible
그런데 그게 가능해졌다.
with all thanks to the genius one-woman army, Ms. Hong.
모두 천재 덕분이에요 1여성군 홍씨.
I thought as much.
나는 그렇게 생각했다.
She hasn't changed a bit.
그녀는 조금도 변하지 않았습니다.
Has Choi In-ja
최인자가 있다
ever asked for President Shin through the admin office?
신 회장에게 요청한 적도 있다 관리사무소를 통해서요?
There were two instances.
두 가지 경우가 있었습니다.
Last week, she set up a dinner.
지난 주에 그녀는 저녁 식사를 준비했습니다.
And today, she left a message.
그리고 오늘 그녀는 메시지를 남겼습니다.
Really?
정말?
She just has to force my hand.
그녀는 단지 내 손을 강요하기만 하면 됩니다.
Surely,
확실히,
they can't be an item, right?
아이템이 될 수는 없잖아요?
Not with her, but with Ms. Kang.
그녀와 함께가 아니라 강씨와 함께요.
It appears Choi In-ja wants him as her son-in-law.
최인자가 원하는 것 같다 그녀의 사위로서.
The president and Nora?
대통령과 노라?
I mean, him and Ms. Kang?
내 말은, 그 사람과 강 씨?
You must let me know immediately once their blind date is set up.
즉시 알려주셔야 합니다 소개팅이 정해지면.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
PERSONAL DETAILS
개인정보
YEHPPEE = INFILTRATOR SO-BANG-CHA
예피 = 침입자 소방차
ELIMINATED AS CANDIDATE
후보에서 제외됨
FOUGHT WITH KANG MYEONG-HWI, BETRAYED KANG MYEONG-HWI
강명휘와 싸웠다. 배신당한 강명휘
THEN WHO IS YEHPPEE?
그렇다면 예피는 누구인가?
NOVEMBER, 1997
1997년 11월
What if the prosecutors come after the Outstanding Women Employees' Club?
검찰이 뒤따르면 어쩌지 우수여성직원클럽?
I doubt they're capable of thinking outside the box.
나는 그들이 할 수 있을지 의심스럽다. 상자 밖에서 생각하기.
The Outstanding Women's Club
뛰어난 여성 클럽
and Song Ju-ran.
그리고 송주란.
Jang-mi, come on out for an emergency roommate meeting.
장미야, 나와라 응급 룸메이트 회의를 위해.
Okay.
좋아요.
I spoke with the children's home director over the phone,
나는 어린이집 원장과 이야기를 나눴다. 전화로,
and they didn't even know Bom had been missing for a week.
그리고 그들은 심지어 몰랐어 봄은 일주일 동안 실종 상태였습니다.
She's been here for a whole week, and they didn't notice she was missing?
그녀는 일주일 내내 여기에 있었어요 그리고 그들은 그녀가 실종된 것을 몰랐나요?
But you didn't know at first, either.
하지만 당신도 처음에는 몰랐어요.
You only found out after she was sick.
당신은 그녀가 아픈 후에야 알게 됐어요.
She's right.
그녀 말이 맞아요.
You didn't know.
당신은 몰랐어요.
Shall we take a short break?
우리 잠시 쉬어갈까요?
I'll be right back, Bom.
금방 돌아올게요, 봄.
We need to get back in there with a solid argument.
우리는 거기로 다시 들어가야 해요 확고한 주장으로.
How will we ever persuade Jang-mi?
장미를 어떻게 설득할 것인가?
You were great earlier.
당신은 일찍부터 훌륭했어요.
She didn't even notice Bom was around.
그녀는 봄이 주변에 있다는 것조차 눈치 채지 못했습니다.
By the way, who is Hong Keum-bo?
그런데 홍금보는 누구인가?
Where did you hear that name?
그 이름을 어디서 들어보셨나요?
You said it.
당신이 말했잖아요.
"Hong Keum-bo!"
"홍금보!"
Get it together, Hong Keum-bo!
힘내라 홍금보!
Damn it.
젠장.
Is there anything else
다른 건 없나요?
that you saw or heard?
당신이 보거나 들었던 것?
Last time, in the big room,
지난번엔 큰방에서
I saw a rectangular…
직사각형을 봤는데..
Rectangular?
직사각형?
It had photos of old guys.
노인들의 사진이 있었어요.
I saw Auntie Bok-hee in there too.
거기에서 복희 이모도 봤어요.
Bom.
봄.
You can't tell anyone about that, okay?
그것에 대해 아무에게도 말하면 안 돼요, 그렇죠?
Please?
제발?
-You do it. -No, you do it.
- 당신이 하세요. -아니요, 당신이 하세요.
Then can you grant my wish?
그럼 내 소원을 들어주실 수 있나요?
I want to live here with my mommy.
나는 여기서 엄마와 함께 살고 싶어요.
I'll keep your secret.
나는 당신의 비밀을 지킬 것입니다.
Fine. Let's make a promise.
괜찮은. 약속합시다.
Mommy!
엄마!
Bom.
봄.
Good job!
잘했어요!
BOM CHILDCARE DUTIES
BOM 보육 의무
GO BOK-HEE: STUDIES AND READING READ HER ONE BOOK A DAY!
고복희: 연구와 독서 하루에 한 권의 책을 읽어보세요!
Ta-da.
짜잔.
-That's Mommy's name. -It is.
- 그건 엄마 이름이에요. -그것은.
That's Auntie Bok-hee.
바로 복희 이모입니다.
What are beeper numbers?
호출기 번호란 무엇입니까?
If you're ever in trouble, you just need to call one of the aunties.
혹시라도 곤란한 일이 생기면, 이모 중 한 명에게 전화하면됩니다.
Now you're even raising a kid?
이제 아이까지 키우시나요?
If you fight it, you'll be taken down in an instant.
맞서 싸우면, 당신은 즉시 쓰러질 것입니다.
Anyhow,
어쨌든,
Cha's situation is as you heard in the recording.
차씨의 상황은 녹음에서 들은 대로요.
Both his father-in-law's bankruptcy and apartment foreclosure were stopped,
두 시아버지의 파산 아파트 압류도 중단됐고,
though it'll be hard to trace since the payment was in cash.
추적하기 힘들겠지만 결제는 현금으로 했기 때문에
Seriously, if it's not one of the So-Bang-Cha trio,
진심으로 그렇지 않다면 소방차 트리오 중 하나,
then who the hell is Yehppee?
그럼 예피는 대체 누구야?
Yehppee could've switched sides after all that happened.
Yehppee는 편을 바꿀 수도 있었어 그 모든 일이 일어난 후에.
Let's expose that slush fund.
그 비자금을 폭로하자.
Up until now, the slush funds hidden domestically were impossible to trace.
지금까지 숨겨져 있던 비자금 국내에서는 추적이 불가능했다.
In the olden days, bank and securities firm employees
옛날에는 은행, 증권사 직원
kept hundreds of fake bankbooks in their desks.
수백개를 보관했다 책상에 가짜 통장.
Now, they're all fired up about the real-name banking system.
이제 다들 열받았어요 은행실명제에 대해서.
Who'd be crazy enough to lend their name nowadays?
누가 충분히 미쳤겠는가 요즘 이름을 빌려주려고?
What if it wasn't borrowed,
빌려준 게 아니라면 어쩌지?
but secretly stolen?
그런데 몰래 훔쳤다고?
I found something suspicious in Cha's recordings.
수상한 걸 발견했어요 Cha의 녹음에서.
That's the Outstanding Women roster.
그것이 뛰어난 여성 명단입니다.
"Outstanding Women"?
"뛰어난 여성"?
HANMIN'S OUTSTANDING WOMEN EMPLOYEES
한민의 우수한 여성직원
Go Bok-hee. Kim I-gyeong.
고복희. 김이경.
Even if their accounts were used to funnel the funds,
자신의 계정이 사용된 경우에도 자금을 조달하기 위해,
Hanmin could've paid them off to play dumb and deny it all.
한민은 그 돈을 갚을 수도 있었어 바보처럼 행동하고 모든 것을 부정합니다.
What then?
그럼 어쩌지?
That's why we need Hong Jang-mi to become an Outstanding Woman
이래서 홍장미가 필요해 뛰어난 여성이 되기 위해
and verify it for ourselves.
그리고 스스로 확인해 보세요.
RESIDENT REGISTRATION CARD KIM I-GYEONG
주민등록카드 김이경
HANMIN INVESTMENT & SECURITIES
한민투자증권
Please forgive me.
용서해주세요.
I just got greedy
그냥 욕심이 났어
after seeing that large sum suddenly appear in my account.
그 큰 금액을 보고 갑자기 내 계정에 나타납니다.
I promise to never do it again.
다시는 그러지 않겠다고 약속합니다.
Please spare me, just this once.
이번 한 번만 살려주세요.
Right.
오른쪽.
So why would you try to take money that isn't even yours?
그럼 왜 돈을 가져가려고 합니까? 그거 네 것도 아니잖아?
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
We took care of Kim I-gyeong's account at the Songwi Branch.
김이경 계정을 처리했습니다 송위지점에서
Good work.
잘했어요.
Yes, ma'am.
네, 부인.
Wait.
기다리다.
Yes?
예?
What an odd resemblance.
정말 이상하게 닮았습니다.
UNDERCOVER MISS HONG
언더커버 미스홍
What? Were you caught?
무엇? 잡혔나요?
Worry about your own risks.
자신의 위험에 대해 걱정하십시오.
I need to hear the answer I never got back then.
대답을 들어야 해 나는 그때 돌아오지 못했다.
Why has Hong Keum-bo lied to plant herself in Hanmin?
홍금보가 왜? 한민에 자신을 심으려고 거짓말을 했다고?
I am Hong Jang-mi, no matter what anyone says.
저는 홍장미입니다. 누가 뭐래도.
You want an Outstanding Woman nomination?
뛰어난 여성 후보로 지명되기를 원하시나요?
Jeez, I was really hoping to avoid setting a honey trap.
이런, 난 정말 피하고 싶었어 꿀 트랩을 설치합니다.
Jang-mi, do you have a date?
장미야, 데이트 있어?
There must be money in my account as well.
내 계좌에도 돈이 있을 거에요.
That money is nothing but trouble.
그 돈은 문제일 뿐이다.
Who in the world is this unidentified male?
세상에 누가 이 신원불명의 남자인가요?
Jang-mi!
장미!
Subtitle translation by: Justin S. Kim
자막 번역: Justin S. Kim